(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
公演ハッシュタグ #hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2
Concert Hashtag #hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will start in a moment.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention For Visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援 OK です
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance / Cheering loudly is OK.
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
hololive EXPO 2025の会場にある特設ブースで、
at the special booth at the hololive EXPO 2025 venue,
展示中の商品をご紹介！
we introduce products currently on display!
ホロライブエキスポ2025限定の一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中！
A special Ichiban Kuji photo booth, exclusive to Hololive Expo 2025, is also open!
モニターをタッチしてくじ券をめくり、出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます。
Touch the monitor to flip the lottery ticket, and take a photo with the design that appears.
(Singing) Last Frontier...
hololive 5th fes. で歌われた
Sung at hololive 5th fes.
The Last Frontierからなんと！
From The Last Frontier, amazingly!
(Singing) ...捧げる歌を
(Singing) ...the song dedicated to you
フィギュア化決定！
Figure production decided!
(Singing) 守り抜いた地平で...
(Singing) On the horizon we protected...
あの感動をもう一度...
That emotion once more...
(Singing) 旅立つ歌を...
(Singing) The song for departing...
スケールフィギュア化決定
Scale figure production decided
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
'Hololive' prizes from FuRyu are appearing one after another at amusement facilities nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
New "Hikkake" figures will also appear starting from April!
Pick from 90 hololive and HOLOSTARS talents
90人のhololiveとHOLOSTARSタレントから好きな1人を選ぼう！
Choose your favorite one from 90 hololive and HOLOSTARS talents!
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
Providing the most convenient payment service while traveling in Taiwan.
新商品まもなく登場！
New product coming soon!
一カ通限定盲包
iPASS Limited Blind Bag
2025年夏 発売予定
Scheduled for release in summer 2025
歌いたい曲が入っていなかった...
The song I wanted to sing wasn't there...
だったらJOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
In that case, let's sing with JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 only one
JOYSOUND X1 曲数No.1
JOYSOUND X1, No. 1 in number of songs
AIが採点 絶賛 カラオケ最高！ 最高！
AI scoring, acclaim, karaoke is the best! The best!
JOYSOUND Evolution 見よ、最高の...
JOYSOUND Evolution, behold, the best...
曲数No.1 歌いたい曲があるって最高！
No. 1 in number of songs, it's the best to have the songs you want to sing!
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください。
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
また、声出し応援はOKです。
Also, cheering out loud is OK.
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is OK.
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
ホロライブ・エキスポ 2025の会場にある特設ブースで
at the special booth in the hololive EXPO 2025 venue,
展示中の商品をご紹介！
we're introducing the products on display!
ホロライブエキスポ2025限定の、
Exclusive to hololive EXPO 2025,
一番くじ特設フォトブースも展開中。
the Ichiban Kuji special photo booth is also now open.
モニターをタッチしてクジ券をめくり、
You can touch the monitor to reveal a lottery ticket
出てきたデザインと一緒に撮影できます。
and take a photo with the design that appears.
The Last Frontier
…して 捧げる歌を…
...and offer this song...
…もう一度…
...once more...
フィギュア化決定！
Figure project decided!
響け 空の彼方へ…
Resonate to the far side of the sky...
支え合いたい The Last Frontier
I want to support you, The Last Frontier
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設にて続々展開中！
hololive prizes from FuRyu are rolling out to amusement centers nationwide!
4月からは新たにひっかけフィギュアも登場！
New 'Hikkake' figures are also coming in April!
90人のhololiveとHOLOSTARSタレントから好きな1人を選ぼう！
Pick your favorite from 90 hololive and HOLOSTARS talents!
3月8日より先行予約開始
Pre-orders start March 8th
台湾旅行中、最も便利な決済サービスを提供します。
We provide the most convenient payment service for your trip to Taiwan.
新商品まもなく登場！
New products coming soon!
歌いたい曲が入っていなかった…
The song I wanted to sing wasn't there...
だったら！
In that case!
JOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ！
Let's sing it on JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 オンデマンド！
JOYSOUND X1 On-demand!
JOYSOUND X1 曲数No.1！
JOYSOUND X1, number one in song count!
AIが採点 絶賛 カラオケ最高！
AI scoring is great, karaoke is the best!
曲数No.1 歌いたい曲があるって最高！
Ranked #1 for song variety! It's the best to have the songs you want to sing!
JOYSOUND X1
タイトー！
Taito!
超特大ぬいぐるみブランド『どきゅーと』から商品化決定！
Announcement: Plushies from the jumbo brand 'Doqute' are coming!
約100cmサイズぬいぐるみに！
They'll be massive, roughly 100cm plushies!
2025年夏受注開始予定！
Orders are scheduled to start in Summer 2025!
タイトー！
Taito!
グルーヴコースター最新作に、白上フブキと、
In the latest Groove Coaster, Shirakami Fubuki and,
さくらみこが、キャラクターボイスで参戦！
Sakura Miko join with character voices!
人気曲や、私たちが歌う曲も楽しめる！
Enjoy popular tracks and songs sung by us!
私たちが、グルーヴワールドをナビゲートするよ！
We'll be your guides to the Groove World!
…もっともっと夢を追いかけたい
...I want to chase my dreams more and more
ワクワクとまらない 想像を超えてく…
The excitement won't stop, exceeding my imagination...
…世界に見せてあげる
...I'll show the whole world
コナミ！
Konami!
ゲームのオアシスに飛び込め！
Dive into the oasis of gaming!
推しの夢叶えます。
Making your oshi's dreams come true.
特報
Special News
2025年夏 コラボカフェ・プライズ開催決定
Collab cafe and prizes coming in Summer 2025
Color Rise Harmony
hololive 6th fes. 応援メッセージ公開中！
hololive 6th fes. support messages now being shown!
Color Rise Harmony hololive 6th fes.
hololive STAGE3
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
公演ハッシュタグ #hololivefes EXPO25_DAY2
Performance Hashtag: #hololivefes EXPO25_DAY2
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
PENLIGHT COLORS
hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony
hololive STAGE 3
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: For Visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
PENLIGHT COLORS
Color Rise Harmony
MUMEI & TOWA WE MISS YOU!
変態会いたい
I want to meet the perverts
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS CAT?
この猫を見たことがある？
CAUSE SHE'S FUGGING ADORABLE
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS CAT?
Have you seen this cat?
CAUSE SHE'S FUGGING ADORABLE
BOAT GOES BINTED
百鬼あやめ
BIG LOVE
Nakiri Ayame
大神ミオ おかえり！
Ookami Mio, welcome back!
フブちゃん 僕らの心の希望!!
100万回... 愛してる!!
Fubu-chan, the hope of our hearts!!
I love you... a million times!!
ときのそら
Tokino Sora
ロボ子さん
Robocosan
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
癒月ちょこ
Yuzuki Choco
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
アイラニ・イオフィフティーン
Airani Iofifteen
アーニャ・メルフィッサ
Anya Melfissa
ベスティア・ゼータ
Vestia Zeta
一伊那尓栖
Ninomae Ina'nis
がうる・ぐら
Gawr Gura
オーロ・クロニー
Ouro Kronii
七詩ムメイ
Nanashi Mumei
hololive 6th fes.
Color Rise Harmony
あの涙が 今も僕らを繋げて
Those tears still connect us now
この心に 君の欠片がいるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart
一人じゃないから
Because I'm not alone
描き足した文字の中
In the letters I added
目を閉じた先に
Beyond my closed eyes
色づく景色が揺れた
The coloring scenery swayed
少し戸惑う風の中
In the slightly confused wind
重なる花びら
Overlapping petals
私たちの声
Our voices
一瞬
A moment
捕まえる未来
Capture the future
もっと
More
踏み出せたなら
If we could step forward
あの涙が 今も僕らを繋げて
Those tears still connect us now
この心に 君の欠片がいるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart
強くなくてもいい
You don't have to be strong
今の光を
The light of now
もっと集め
Gathering more
空に放つ
Release into the sky
この奇跡を 僕らで今輝かせるから
Because we'll make this miracle shine now
力が湧くから
Because power wells up
溢れた手も 握りしめ
Clutching the overflowing hands
遠い未来へと
Toward the distant future
強く願い込め舞い上がれ
Soar with strong wishes
音の風を 吹かせては
Letting the wind of sound blow
理想の花びら
The ideal petals
彩る明日の空
Coloring tomorrow's sky
何百億も 光る星みたいに
Like billions of shining stars
ずっと
Always
終わらないから
Because it will never end
この笑顔が 過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile tightly embraces the past
今未来に この手伸ばしていくから
Because I'm stretching out my hand to the future now
飛び込めるんだ
I can dive in
空を見上げよう
Let's look up at the sky
笑い響き渡っていく
Laughter goes echoing through
次の夢も 掴みとるって約束するから
Because I promise to grasp the next dream too
踏み出そうここから
Let's step forward from here
We are
with you
見えない色を見ていたい
I want to see the invisible colors
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
We are, we are with you
Capture the moment
ソロトップはラミィ！
Solo top is Lamy!
声出せ！雪民たち！
Make some noise! Yukimin!
この6th Fesを全力で
With all our might in this 6th Fes...
楽しんでいきたいかー！
...do you want to have fun?!
ハイハイハイ！じゃあみんな突っ立ってないで
Alright! Now everyone, don't just stand there!
推しぬい持って、ペンラ持って、行くよ！
Grab your plushies and penlights! Let's go!
ヨレもマッスル
Fatigue is muscle!
止まらないワッツアップ
Unstoppable what's up!
3, 2, 1, レッツゴー！
3, 2, 1, Let's go!
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle! No Life!
ノーキンニクッピナピナス
No-muscle-pina-pinas
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle! No Life! No Muscle! No Life!
倍速度でマッチョマッチョ
Macho macho at double speed!
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle! No Life! No Muscle! No Life!
止まらせんでパンプアップ
Don't let it stop, pump up!
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle! No Life! No Muscle! No Life!
今日も今日とてマッチョマッチョ、レッツ！
Macho macho today as well, let's!
夢中もギュッとした本能ボレ
Instinctive fall, also squeezed with infatuation
向かう先目標定め
Set the goal for the destination
パチポコ手を叩け
Pachi-poko clap your hands
ドンドコ足鳴らせ
Don-doko stomp your feet
とにかく追い込んだら しきれ限界まで！
Just push yourself until the limit!
ムキムキなラミィ カチカチでバニー
Muscular Lamy, rock-hard bunny
ほてってるセレナーデ
Flushed serenade
ほらね祝福パワー 様になってるテンション
See, blessing power, the tension is getting there
見せびらかせて！
Show it off!
見上げれば光るダイヤモンド
Looking up, a shining diamond
ヨレもマッスル
Fatigue is muscle!
止まらないワッツアップ
Unstoppable what's up!
なりたい なりたい なりたいの？
Do you want to be, want to be, want to be?
理想の体になりたいの？
Do you want to have the ideal body?
ワガママボディに宿教える
Teaching your selfish body
夢の中までご褒美レッスン
Reward lesson until inside your dreams
お疲れ様、今日も頑張ってるね。
Good job, you're working hard today too.
やる気がよろしい、えらいえらい。
Your motivation is good, great, great.
さあ、これから一緒にみんなも
Now, together with me, will everyone...
トレーニング、やってくれるかな？
...do some training?
足を肩幅に開いて、手を前にして
Open your feet shoulder-width, put your hands forward
芝刈りパンプアップ、始めるよ！
Lawnmower Pump Up, let's begin!
ブン！バリバリバリバリ！ブン！バリバリバリバリ！
BUN! BARI-BARI-BARI-BARI! BUN! BARI-BARI-BARI-BARI!
芝刈りパンプアップとは、あれで芝刈り機を
Lawnmower Pump Up is, as if operating a lawnmower...
操るかの如く、上下左右に体を動かすことにより
By moving your body up, down, left, and right...
肉体の至るところにシックスパックを溜めていく
Accumulating six-packs throughout your body...
合理的で超天才的なトレーニングなのだ！
...it's a rational and super genius training!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
笑顔と気合とメンタルでがんばれ
Keep at it with a smile, spirit, and mental strength!
いくよ！
Here I go!
ムキムキの実 ポキポキでボディ
Muscular fruit, a crackling body
さあ 燃えるさ明日だ
Now, tomorrow is burning
ほら 誰かれも 振り返るでしょうね 見せつけてやろう
Look, everyone will look back, won't they? Let's show them what we've got!
腰にはヴィーナス・バップ
Venus Bappu on my waist
やれんのかお前と止まらないわくわく
Can you do it? This excitement with you won't stop
やるしかないでしょう バリバリでわくわく
We have to do it, right? Full-power excitement
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle No Life! No Muscle No Life!
ノー筋肉 ヴィーナス・ヴィーナス
No Muscle Venus Venus
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle No Life! No Muscle No Life!
お隣さんも マッチョマッチョ
The neighbor is also macho, macho
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle No Life! No Muscle No Life!
やる気 本気 大好き
Motivation, seriousness, I love it!
ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！ノー筋肉！ノーライフ！
No Muscle No Life! No Muscle No Life!
頑張る君と マッチョマッチョ Yeah!
With you doing your best, macho macho yeah!
マッチョ！
Macho!
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
We'll keep running through no matter how far we go
傷つけて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we hurt others or get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いもいつかのための正解でしょう
Mistakes are probably the right answers for some day
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ 行くんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's fine to be clumsy. Now, let's go.
閉ざされたこの世界で 繰り返すだけの毎日
In this closed-off world, days just repeating
言えずにいた言葉を 風に乗せてひとり呟いた
I whispered to myself the words I couldn't say, letting the wind carry them
素直になるためには まだまだ勇気が足りないけど
I still don't have enough courage to be honest, but...
水しぶき上げて飛び込んだ 目を瞑りながら
I jumped in, splashing water, while closing my eyes
悪戦苦闘に虹を描いて 青を塗りつぶした
Drawing a rainbow in the struggle, I painted over the blue
扉開けて 飛び出そうよ 決めもして未来へ
Let's open the door and jump out, towards the undecided future
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
We'll keep running through no matter how far we go
傷つけて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we hurt others or get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いもいつかのための正解でしょう
Mistakes are probably the right answers for some day
顔を上げて走り出そうよ ひとりぼっちがふたりで
Let's lift our heads and start running, the two of us who were alone
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ 行くんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's fine to be clumsy. Now, let's go.
正解で不正解かも 時々わからなくなって
It might be right or wrong, sometimes I don't know
涙こらえながら 答えを探し続けてたんだ
I kept searching for the answer while holding back tears
溢れた涙 見つけた笑顔 全部宝箱に仕まって
All the overflowing tears and found smiles, I'll put them in a treasure chest
いつか立ち止まったら 思い出してまた笑いたいな
If I ever stop one day, I want to remember and laugh again
満天の星空を描いて 願い事をしよう
Let's draw a starry sky and make a wish
流れ星も書き足そうか 僕次第で変えられるんだ
Shall we add a shooting star? I can change it depending on me
いつまでもこの日々が 続くといいな
I hope these days last forever
望んだって叶わないことだらけでも 悪くないな
Even if it's full of things that won't come true, it's not bad
明日へとこの歌が 届くといいな
I hope this song reaches tomorrow
手を取って笑い合って ありのままを描いていくんだ
We'll hold hands, laugh together, and keep drawing things as they are
どこまでも僕ら駆け抜けていくんだ
We'll keep running through no matter how far we go
傷つけて傷ついたって 明日は笑っていたいな
Even if we hurt others or get hurt, I want to be laughing tomorrow
間違いもいつかのための正解だから
Because mistakes are the right answers for some day
顔を上げて走り出そうよ ひとりぼっちがふたりで
Let's lift our heads and start running, the two of us who were alone
転んだって泣いたって不器用でいいじゃん さあ 行くんだ
Even if we fall or cry, it's fine to be clumsy. Now, let's go.
きっと未来は色に溢れ
Surely the future will be full of color
まだ見ぬ世界を
The world yet unseen
カラフルに染める
Will be dyed colorfully
本当自由になりたいから
Because I really want to be free
ずっと ずっと ずっと
Forever, forever, forever
夢見てるの
I'm dreaming
空に光る星のように
Like the stars shining in the sky
輝きたいと願う夜
On nights I wish to shine
広い世界に存在を
My existence in this wide world
証明したくて
I want to prove it
出来ないことばっか数えても
Even if I only count the things I can't do
胸が苦しくなるだけでしょ
It'll only make my heart ache
私だって絶対
Even I, definitely
あの日の夢のようになれるはず
Should be able to become like that day's dream
響く音色の中
Amidst the echoing tones
ほら 未知なる景色
Look, an unknown scenery
ふと感じてたのに
Though I suddenly felt it
気がしてたんだ
I had a feeling
そっと伸ばしたこの手の先
Beyond this hand I gently reached out
描いた理想が想像を越える
The ideal I drew exceeds imagination
きっと見つける私の色
Surely I'll find my color
ずっと ずっと ずっと
Forever, forever, forever
追いかけるの
I'll chase after it
限りなく不透明だった
It was infinitely opaque
瞳に映る全て
Everything reflected in my eyes
変わりゆく世界のリズムに乗って
Riding the rhythm of the changing world
モノクロを染めてゆく
Dyeing the monochrome
閉じ込めなくていいの
It's okay not to lock it away
不安感じても
Even if I feel anxious
私だけの色で描こう
Let's draw with only my colors
きっと未来は色に溢れ
Surely the future will be full of color
まだ見ぬ世界はカラフルに染まる
The world yet unseen will be dyed colorfully
もっと自由に羽ばたくから
Because I'll flap my wings more freely
ずっと あの日感じたままに
Forever, just as I felt that day
そっと伸ばしたこの手の先
Beyond this hand I gently reached out
夢見た理想が想像を越える
The ideal I dreamed of exceeds imagination
やっと見つけた私の色
Finally I found my color
ずっと ずっと ずっと
Forever, forever, forever
描いてゆくの
I'll keep drawing it
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and make merry, the banquet continues
舞えよ鬼狐狼
Dance, Oni, Fox, Wolf
いえー！みんなー！あやふみがきたぞー！
Yay! Everyone! Ayafumi is here!
たくさんコールしてねー！
Call out a lot!
いくよー！
Here we go!
せーの！
Ready, set...
鬼狐狼忍者！
Oni, Fox, Wolf, Ninja!
一二三で七変化
One, two, three, and a seven-fold transformation
今宵も集えインターネット
Gather again tonight on the internet
お仕事に幸あれ
Blessings upon your work
ここはまるで桃源郷
It's just like a Xanadu here
いっせーのでヨイヨイ！
All together now, yoi-yoi!
浮世に隠れず舞い光る
Dancing and shining without hiding in the transient world
どっちでも良い良い！
Either way is fine-fine!
我が道を行け
Go your own way
ゆらゆらに恋焦がれ
Deeply in love, swaying
刹那にも揺るこの想いは
This feeling that wavers even for a moment
まだ分からないけど
I don't know yet, but
実らせて
Make it bear fruit
咲き乱れよ
Bloom in profusion
お人目憚らぬ 祭り囃子
A festival tune that pays no heed to others' eyes
小生意気常も 飛び回れ
Fly around even in cheeky times
命は短し　我武者羅に刻め
Life is short, carve it recklessly
一富士二鷹三は鬼
One Fuji, two hawks, three is Oni
千客万来　おいでませ
A constant stream of guests, please come in
あっぱれ　お祭りじゃ
Splendid! It's a festival!
打ちまくれ
Drum away!
謳え宴　宴は続く　舞え　アニマルダンス
Sing the banquet, the banquet continues, dance, animal dance
言いたいことがあるんだよ！
There's something I want to say!
やっぱりケモ耳かわいいよ！
As expected, animal ears are cute!
コンコン、ゴー！　メチャカッコ！
Kon Kon, Go! Super cool!
やっと見つけたお嬢様！
Finally found the young lady!
僕等と未来へ繋いで行こう！
Let's connect to the future with us!
夢を追いかけ　何処までも
Chasing dreams, no matter where
世界で一番愛してる！
I love you the most in the world!
あ・い・し・て・るー！
I-l-o-v-e-y-o-u-!
踊りましょう
Let's dance
鬼と負けじと舞い踊れ　小生意気な狐も飛び回れ
Dance like an Oni without losing, the cheeky fox also flies around
命は短し　我武者羅に刻め
Life is short, carve it recklessly
一富士二鷹三は鬼
One Fuji, two hawks, three is Oni
千客万来　おいでませ
A constant stream of guests, please come in
あっぱれ　お祭りじゃ
Splendid! It's a festival!
打ちまくれ
Drum away!
謳え宴　宴は続く　舞え　アニマルダンス
Sing the banquet, the banquet continues, dance, animal dance
色づく想いは刹那　百花繚乱　花吹雪
Colorful thoughts are momentary, blooming in profusion, a blizzard of flowers
2階席も行きますよー！　みんな　声出せー！
We're going to the 2nd floor seats too! Everyone, raise your voices!
パッと咲いて散った花は　終焉を告げてく
The flowers that bloomed and scattered quickly signal the end
その時を待てど暮らせど　言葉　紡がず
Waiting for that time day in and day out, words remain unspun
そっと触れて知った胸の内　温かさを
The warmth I felt in my heart when I touched it softly
初めてのこの気持ちだけ　抱きしめていた
Just this first-time feeling, I was holding it tight
暁　交わした約束は　本物だってきっと
The promise we made at dawn is surely real
信じてる
I believe
いろはにほへと　花に魅せられた少女達
Iroha ni hoheto, girls charmed by flowers
あぁ　はらりはらりはらり　落ちる花吹雪　踊れ
Ah, harari harari harari, the falling blizzard of flowers, dance
うたかたであれど　想い　言の葉に込めてみた
Though it's fleeting, I tried putting my thoughts into words
誰も皆　焦がれる　現世の理よ
Everyone yearns for it, the logic of this world
色づく想いは刹那　百花繚乱　花吹雪
Colorful thoughts are momentary, blooming in profusion, a blizzard of flowers
ひぃふぅみぃ数えて　ひぃふぅみぃ数えて
Counting one, two, three... counting one, two, three...
ここへおいで　ここへおいで
Come over here... come over here...
暁　交わした約束は　本物だってきっと
The promise we made at dawn is surely real
信じてる
I believe
いろはにほへと　花に魅せられた少女達
Iroha ni hoheto, girls charmed by flowers
あぁ　はらりはらりはらり　落ちる花吹雪　踊れ
Ah, harari harari harari, the falling blizzard of flowers, dance
うたかたであれど　想い　言の葉に込めてみた
Though it's fleeting, I tried putting my thoughts into words
誰も皆　焦がれる　現世の理よ
Everyone yearns for it, the logic of this world
色づく想いは刹那　百花繚乱　花吹雪
Colorful thoughts are momentary, blooming in profusion, a blizzard of flowers
風に舞う　乙女の純情　咲き誇れ
A maiden's pure heart dancing in the wind, bloom in full pride
イェーイ！
Yay!
自由自由！
Free, free!
ストップストップ！配信の所、所！
Stop, stop! The stream section, section!
ご挨拶、ご挨拶。はい、まずはあやめから、はいどうぞ！
Greetings, greetings. Okay, first from Ayame, go ahead!
はい！みんな、いろはにほへと　あやふぶみの　あや担当、百鬼あやめだぞー！
Yes! Everyone, I'm Nakiri Ayame, the "Aya" in charge of Iroha Ni Hoheto Ayafubumi!
そしてー！
And!
はい！いろはにほへと　あやふぶみの　ふぶ担当、白上フブキです！
Yes! I'm Shirakami Fubuki, the "Fubu" in charge of Iroha Ni Hoheto Ayafubumi!
そしてそしてー！
And and!
はい！いろはにほへと　あやふぶみの　み担当、大神ミオです！
Yes! I'm Ookami Mio, the "Mi" in charge of Iroha Ni Hoheto Ayafubumi!
そして、3人揃って...
And, all three of us together...
いろはにほへと　あやふぶみでーす！
We are Iroha Ni Hoheto Ayafubumi!
ちょっとちょっと、なんかあや...
Wait wait, something about Aya...
フブミでござるの久しぶりじゃないですか？
Isn't it the first time in a while for Fubumi?
よかったー！
That was great!
気持ちいい！
Felt good!
よかったね、今年。
It was good this year, wasn't it?
百花繚乱さ...
About Hyakka Ryouran...
最初さ、ちょっとあの裏話になってしまうんですけど、
At first, this is a bit of a behind-the-scenes story, but
ま、曲こうやってメドレーにしようって決めたじゃないですか？
we decided to make the songs into a medley like this, right?
はい。
Yes.
百花繚乱と振り付け覚えてる？って。
I asked, "Do you remember the choreography for Hyakka Ryouran?"
「色づいた思いは」って。
"The colors of my feelings..."
練習の時ちょっと焦ったよ。
I was a bit panicked during practice.
そうそうそう。「えーっと...」みたいな。
Right, right. Like, "Uh... wait..."
そう！
Exactly!
あとこれの...
And also for this...
そうそうそう、右か左か忘れちゃって。
yeah, I forgot if it was right or left.
わかるわかる！
I know, I know!
あと順番ね！
And the order!
これ、これ。
This one, then this one.
あ、これだ！
Ah, this is it!
「色づいた思いは」...
"The colors of my feelings..."
で、でも久しぶりにこれができたよね。
but we were able to do this after a long time.
「百花繚乱」！
"Hyakka Ryouran"!
これは流石に覚えてた。
We definitely remembered this part.
余もめちゃめちゃ楽しませていただきました。
I also had a lot of fun.
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you very much!
はい、さてね、とうとう皆さん、
Alright, and now everyone,
フェスも最後、STAGE3でございます！
finally, the last part of the fes, Stage 3!
STAGE3なんですか！？
It's Stage 3!?
そうでございます。
That's right.
明日STAGE4があるってことですか？
Does that mean there's a Stage 4 tomorrow?
え？明日STAGE4？
Eh? Stage 4 tomorrow?
え、まだあるってこと？
There's more?
ないないない！何言ってんだよ！
No, no, no! What are you talking about!?
ないの？
There's none?
そんなー！
No way!
ないですよー！もう我々でライブは最後です！
There isn't! This is the final live performance for us!
えええー！？
EHHH!?
なんですけども、STAGE3の皆だいぶ気合入ってるので皆さんね、
But everyone in Stage 3 is really fired up, so everyone,
マジでコール負けねえように頑張ってくださいよ！
please do your best so you don't lose out on the calls!
頑張ってー！
Good luck!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
よし、しょっぱなのラミィのね。
Alright, Lamy was at the very beginning.
ね！
Right!
バリバリ！
Rocking it!
バリバリやりましたね、皆さん。
She really rocked it, didn't she everyone?
わかとう。
Indeed.
ね、バリバリからのスバルのエモさが半端なくて。
Right, and after "Baribari", Subaru's emotional impact was incredible.
エモは大爆発。
An explosion of emotion.
そう。
Yeah.
よかったねミオも。
You were great too, Mio.
はい、よかったー。
Yes, it was good.
よかったよー。
You were great.
ちょっと珍しく爽やかな曲です。
It's a refreshingly bright song, which is rare for me.
でも今回のColor Rise Harmonyのテーマにすごく合ってる曲だなって。
But I think it's a song that really fits the theme of "Color Rise Harmony".
えー、確かに！
Ah, definitely!
そう！
Yeah!
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
ね、色づいていくね、この景色がすごく綺麗だなって思いましたよ。
I thought this scenery becoming more colorful was so beautiful.
へへ、なんか照れるな。
Hehe, it's a bit embarrassing.
さてさてさて、ま、このMCもあまり時間がないんですけども。
Well, well, well, we don't have much time for this MC section.
え、そうなんですか？
Eh, is that so?
そうですよ。でもせっかく我々MCやらせていただいてるので、
That's right. But since we're doing this MC section,
やっぱりコールアンドレスポンスしたいですよね！
we definitely want to do a call and response!
ちょっと待ってください。うちはさっきCreators Stageでコールアンドレスポンスやりましたので、うちからやらせていただきたいと思います。
Wait a moment. Since I just did a call and response on the Creators Stage, I'd like to go first.
あ、そうだそうだ。
Ah, that's right.
見せてくれるんですか？
Will you show us?
お手本見せたいと思います。
She wants to show us an example.
お手本お願いします。
Please show us how it's done.
それでは皆さん、うちが「うち、うち、うちだよ」と言ったら、
Alright everyone, when I say "It's me, me, me!",
みんなが「大神ミオだよ」って。
you all say "It's Ookami Mio!"
おてほ...みんながミオちゃん？
An exam... Everyone is Mio-chan?
みんながミオちゃんってこと？
Does that mean everyone becomes Mio-chan?
みんながミオちゃんたちこれ？
Is everyone Mio-chan for this?
まあまあ、あのやってもらえばわかるから。
Well, you'll understand once you do it.
OK、OK。
OK, OK.
お願いしますね、皆さん。
Please, everyone.
じゃあ行きますよ。
Alright, here I go.
うち、うち、うちだよー！
It's me, me, me!
大神ミオだよー！
IT'S OOKAMI MIO!
お前らが大神ミオだー！
YOU ALL are Ookami Mio!
えー、喜んでる。
Eh, they're happy.
すごい喜んでる。
They're so happy.
うちってこと？
Me?
ミオちゃんってこと？
Mio-chan?
うち、うち。
Me, me.
はい、じゃあこれじゃあコレスできそう？
Alright, can we do the call and response now?
お嬢、お嬢さんいっときます？
Ojou, Ojou, will you go next?
え、いいですか？
Eh, is it okay?
お嬢コールは？
What's Ojou's call?
何言っ...ちょっと今日ね、みんなこの衣装着てますでしょう？
What should I... well today, everyone is wearing these outfits, right?
そうだ！
That's right!
え、今日の余どうかな？って聞いたらみんなわかるかな？
If I ask "How do I look today?", will everyone know what to say?
みんなわかるよね？
You all know, right?
かわよー！
Cute!
OK、OK。いい感じ、いい感じ。行きますよ！
OK, OK. Looking good. Here I go!
じゃ、今日の余どうかなー？
So, how do I look today?
かわよー！
SO CUTE!
ありがとう！かわよだよ！
Thank you! You're the cute ones!
へへへ。
Hehehe.
やったーかわよ。
I'm glad, kawayo.
かわよだ。
So cute.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ最後に。
Alright, lastly.
白上もさ、いつも定番なのはさ「100万回愛してる」なんですけども、
For me, the standard one is "I love you a million times", but,
ちょっと二人にはさ、フブキングダムの国民になってもらおうかな？
I'd like to have you two become citizens of Fubuki Kingdom.
え？そうなんですか？
Eh? Really?
今日も...ちょっとソロライブが終わってしまった後で大変恐縮なんですけど、ソロライブの気持ちでいさせてください。
Even though my solo live ended today, and I'm very sorry, please let me keep that feeling of the solo live.
今日今みんないるここにいるみんな、フブキングダムの国民ということで、白上がですね、
Everyone who is here today, you are all citizens of Fubuki Kingdom. And so, I...
ちょみんなもちょっとポーズやってほしいんですけども。
I want everyone to do a pose as well.
ほうほう。
Oh, okay.
こう右手を胸にあて...
Put your right hand over your heart like this...
「フブキングダムに栄光あれ！」っていうこのポーズですね。
and do this pose, saying "Glory to Fubuki Kingdom!"
フブキングダムに栄光あれ！
Glory to Fubuki Kingdom!
これを一緒にやってほしいです。
I want you to do this with me.
オッケー。
OK.
じゃあみんな、構え！構え！
Everyone, ready! Ready!
フブキングダムに...栄光あれー！
Glory to... Fubuki Kingdom-!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
や、気持ちいいな。
Wow, that felt good.
流石に...流石に気持ちいいですね。
Truly... it truly feels good.
じゃ国民解散！
Alright, citizens dismissed!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ま、ね、皆さんそれぞれ推しがいますからね。
Well, everyone has their own favorites after all.
ということでなんやかんやしておりますと、なんと！
And while we've been doing this and that, unexpectedly!
無料パートがここまで！
The free-to-watch part ends here!
えええー！？
EHHH-!?
そんな！嘘だろ！？
No way! You're kidding!?
終わっちゃうの？
It's ending?
終わっちゃうということなので、
Since it's coming to an end,
まあよろしければ皆さんですね、配信で見ている皆さんは
well, if you'd like, for those of you watching the stream,
概要欄から是非とも配信チケットをご購入いただけると嬉しいです！
we'd be happy if you'd purchase a streaming ticket from the description box!
待ってまーす！またねー！
We'll be waiting! See ya!
そしてそして！ハッシュタグ #ホロライブフェスEXPO25_DAY2 でもいっぱいポストしてください！
And also! Please post lots of times with the hashtag #hololivefesEXPO25_DAY2!
いっぱいつぶやいてー
Tweet lots!
お願いします！
Please do!
ということでですね。ではですね、このまま皆さん、精一杯楽しんでいきましょう！
And so, everyone, let's keep having the time of our lives!
おー！
Yeah!
じゃあ、今回のシメの挨拶いきますよ！せーの！
Now, let's do the final greeting for this time! Ready, and...
せーの！
Ready, and...
Color Rise Harmony!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.
無料パートは終了いたしました！
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended.
Thank you for watching.